Now let's see a simple example.
现在 让我们一起来看一个简单例子
I have already created the named array for
我已经在这里设置好了名称
the cells to correspond with the column headers.
作为各列的标题
So, here we have year in the name box,
比如 在这一列的名称框里 "year" 表示年份
we have total revenue, cost of revenue,
还有 "total_revenue" 表示总收入 而 "cost_of_revenue" 表示营收成本
SGAs, R and D,
"SGAs" 表示销售、总务与行政支出 "R_and_D" 则表示研发
and other operating items.
"Other_operating_items" 表示其他经营支出
As part of index,
建立这个索引时
this is what I want to do.
我想做的是
I want to be able to pull for this particular ticker symbol,
单独拉出某个股票代码
the appropriate total revenue,
在 "第一年" (Year 1) 的列中显示相应的总收入、
cost of revenue, SGA,
营收成本、SGA、
R and D, and other operating items for year one.
研发以及其他经营支出
So, it shows up like this.
就像这样
So, keep in mind this is horizontal.
起初的表格当中 这些信息是一个横行
It's the very first row.
是第一行
Each row indicating a different item in the financial statement,
每一行表示财务报表中不同的项
but we want to convert it to a vertical array.
现在 如果想要将其转换成一个纵列
So, how do we go about doing that?
要怎么做呢 ?
So, I've placed all the formulas here so you can follow me along,
我把所有公式都列在这里 便于大家理解
and this is how we use the index.
INDEX 公式的写法
We've already defined the array from which we want to pull the values.
对于要提取数值的列 我们已经进行了命名
This is how we want to be if we wanted,
我们现在想要
from this array, you want the very first value.
引用这一列的第一个值
From this array, we want the very first value to be
那我们就进行操作 引用这一列的第一个值
pulled into each of these cells. So, this is how you do it.
将它填入对应的单元格 步骤如下
So, you'll say equal index.
填入 = index
One way to do it is to select the array,
其实可以选择对应的范围
but keep in mind that I've actually already named it.
但是我之前已经命名了那个范围
So, I'm going to actually just call it up.
所以 现在在函数里输入它的名称即可
So, the way to call it up is you say, total.
先输入 "total"
So, you start typing in the word,
可以看到 输入这个词的时候
and it shows up with this icon.
就会显示出一个小图标 旁边是我们想引用那个范围的名称
You can select that,
选择该名称
and it puts that in the array parameter.
就自动填到函数中了
Then for row number,
然后填行号
we just want the very first row.
我们只想要第一行
We don't have a column specification,
且没有指定列
so because it's one array,
那么
we're going to say one for the row number,
我们在行号这里输入 1
and we close the bracket.
然后输入右括号
Keep in mind there's one final step.
要记得 输入公式之后还有最后一步
You have to Control, Shift,
得同时按下电脑键盘上的
and Enter on the PC,
Control、Shift、Enter 键
and it puts the value in.
才会代入对应的值
I repeat the same for the rest of the cells.
其余单元格也重复同样的步骤
I start typing cost of revenue, one,
这里的范围参数是 cost of revenue 而行号参数是 1
and I press Control, Shift,
然后按下 Control、Shift、Enter 键
Enter, and I believe it's the same on the mark.
在 Mac 电脑上的操作应该也是一样的
Index, gross, this is actually going to be
然后填写 Index gross 哦 错了 这一格应该填数学公式 不是直接引用
our formula because this is revenue minus COGS,
它表示的是收入减去销货成本
and it's blue because I prepopulated the blue format,
我在这一格预先设了蓝色字体
because it's a calculation we're doing here.
提示我们要进行数学计算
Then here, I do index SGA.
下一格输入 index SGA
I can select it from my name box,
选择名称框里的名称
one, Control Shift Enter,
行号参数为 1 然后按下 Control、Shift、Enter 键
and I keep going on to the other row,
另外几行也是类似
which is the other operating expenses,
这一行是其他经营项目支出
and finally to chip direct.
最后是研发
For the total operating expenses,
对于营业总支出
I just add up these three,
只需要把这三项加起来
and operating income is gross profit minus the total operating expenses,
而将毛利润减去营业总支出
which gives us the operating income, or EBIT.
就得出营业收益 也即息税前利润 (EBIT)
So, this is how you do an index function.
这就是 Index 函数的用法